<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Amaryllis</title>
	<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/</link>
	<description>Recent content on Amaryllis</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
    
        <atom:link href="https://amaryllisc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title></title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/addiction/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/addiction/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;addictions&#34;&gt;Addictions&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title></title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/korean/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/korean/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;한국어-배우기&#34;&gt;한국어 배우기&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;할일-todo-list&#34;&gt;할일 (todo list)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a book/course below to follow:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;week: review chapter independently and meet with mom for review/test (1 hr, tentatively on Wednesdays 8pm)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goal for this week (6/24): &amp;ldquo;getting ready&amp;rdquo; of Korean Grammar in Use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;schedule weekly sessions to go through lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources-i-searched&#34;&gt;resources I searched&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/Korean&#34;&gt;r/Korean subreddit for learning Korean&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/Korean/wiki/index&#34;&gt;sub wiki&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/Korean/comments/hw4gy0/the_ultimate_beginners_resource_thread/&#34;&gt;beginner resource thread&lt;/a&gt;, mostly reproduced below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.koreanwikiproject.com/wiki/index.php?title=Learn_hangeul&#34;&gt;koreanwikiproject&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://storylearning.com/learn/korean#korean_pitfalls&#34;&gt;pitfalls to avoid learning korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;문법-수업-sites-with-grammar-lessons-or-courses&#34;&gt;문법 수업 (sites with grammar lessons or courses)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://talktomeinkorean.com/&#34;&gt;talk to me in korean (pay)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtostudykorean.com/&#34;&gt;howtostudykorean (free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nuri.iksi.or.kr/front/main/main.do&#34;&gt;King Sejong Institute Courses (세종학당재단)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;교과서-textbooks&#34;&gt;교과서 (textbooks)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/8959951986&#34;&gt;korean grammar in use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1497445825&#34;&gt;Korean Made Simple: a beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/8976995775&#34;&gt;소강 한국어&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B08N5GGB73/&#34;&gt;Basic Korean: A Grammar and Workbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/0824876199&#34;&gt;Integrated Korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;online-dictionarytranslation-tools&#34;&gt;online dictionary/translation tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.dict.naver.com/#/main&#34;&gt;Naver Dictionary&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href=&#34;https://dict.naver.com/&#34;&gt;Korean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://krdict.korean.go.kr/eng/mainAction?nation=eng&#34;&gt;National Institute of Korean Language Popular alternative&lt;/a&gt;, built for Korean language learners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dic.daum.net/index.do&#34;&gt;daum dictionary&lt;/a&gt; (slightly less information than Naver, but easier to use?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;단어집-vocabulary&#34;&gt;단어집 (vocabulary)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I am keen on memorizing stuff and not really intimidated by it, my impression is it&amp;rsquo;s best to learn vocabulary slowly and in concert with grammar. Korean tends to rely heavily on idioms and using words (particularly verbs and adverbs) in ways which do not directly correspond to the English usage. Thus, mass-memorizing vocabulary may only prove foolhardy, and will result in an awkward Korean (which Koreans will mostly understand and forgive) but which is obviously foreign. The goal for me is to, to the best of my ability, speak and use as the natives do, and hide the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m a foreigner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the goal should be to first have a small vocabulary arsenal, but to be able to employ such an arsenal flawlessly in grammar and sentences. Only then do you build up and learn more words, thus emulating how a native child learns the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular apps/flash card tools used by language learners for vocab include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ankiweb.net/&#34;&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.memrise.com/en-us/&#34;&gt;memrise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;목표-suggested-benchmarksgoals-in-increasing-order-of-difficulty&#34;&gt;목표 (suggested benchmarks/goals, in increasing order of difficulty)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first learn all the grammar rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being able to write a simple letter to someone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being able to read a simple book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Test_of_Proficiency_in_Korean&#34;&gt;Test of Proficiency in Korean (TOPIK)&lt;/a&gt; used to measure 한글 proficiency for foreigners in Korea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;딥스-and-디노-goals&#34;&gt;딥스 and 디노 goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;misc-thoughtscontrarian-wisdom-on-learning-languages&#34;&gt;misc. thoughts/contrarian wisdom on learning languages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Pronunciation&lt;/strong&gt;: to achieve proper pronunciation, one really needs to &amp;ldquo;prepare phonologically&amp;rdquo; for it, which involves changing their mindset from English pronunciation. Sometimes, people are afraid to do this for appearing too tryhard or for fear of messing up. We all know the apathetic American jockbro in Spanish class who almost deliberately pronounced every word in a non-Spanish accent. Sometimes, they do this out of anxiety because it actually sounds more natural to them, and they don&amp;rsquo;t want to look like an idiot who speaks in a &amp;ldquo;foreign&amp;rdquo; accent. Americans have this narcissism because foreigners come to America trying to emulate an American accent and phonology. But, it&amp;rsquo;s complete folly: to any native Spanish speaker, you would sound like an idiot speaking in that accent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One trick some say is that you should think of the most stereotypical accent/pronunciation for that language and speak in that accent when using the language. While you may sound &amp;ldquo;tryhard&amp;rdquo; to Americans, to natives of that language you will sound so much more natural and less weird. This is, of course, predicated on having a familiarity of what the stereotypical sounds in that language are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you actually thinking?&lt;/strong&gt;: language nerds love to opine about their gargantuan index card stack or about the volumes of media they&amp;rsquo;ve consumed, but an important matter often ignored (yet more identifiably linked to fluency) is whether you&amp;rsquo;re able to think in the language, and ultimately this should be the goal of true fluency. After building up a basic repertoire of grammar and vocabulary, the language should become part and parcel of your day-to-day. You should try to think in it, you should try to subconsciously translate english phrases you see to that language, you should try (and inevitably stumble and fail) to create new sentences and phrases using the words and grammar you know. If you mutter about this or that, do so in the language. Note this can be done even if you have no conversation partners and are not immersed in an environment apt for practicing the language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a misconception that children learn languages easily by mere virtue of just &amp;ldquo;consuming a lot of media&amp;rdquo;. Yes, consuming media helps. But, children also have a lot of social motivation to try very hard to &lt;em&gt;participate in&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;produce&lt;/em&gt; conversation, whether that be aloud or even in thought. To learn as fluidly as they do requires a similar courage (read: willingness to fail) and enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Translating to English will make less sense the better you get&lt;/strong&gt;: poorly designed language courses in American education often set the goal of developing an unwieldy rube goldberg engine for understanding and using the language &lt;em&gt;through English&lt;/em&gt;. This is evidenced by the inordinate focus on vocabulary memorization, which are always first translated into (and so necessarily &lt;em&gt;mediated via&lt;/em&gt;) English and the hilariously complicated mnemonic devices and songs to learn simple concepts in the target language. So, the language is treated as mere mental drudgery, no different than some arcane trivia you need to regurgitate for a history test. I&amp;rsquo;d even argue this makes sense for the most popular languages learned by Americans, e.g. Spanish, French, Italian, as they&amp;rsquo;re morphologically quite similar to English (and so can be used near fluently in such a plug-and-play manner), but likely not so for more distant languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children who learn the language natively obviously don&amp;rsquo;t learn this way, and instead learn via proper immersion and a willingness to think in that language as per the above point. And so, I feel a language like Korean should actually just be a different way of thinking and the better you get at it, the less sense it will make to translate it into English. In fact, this is a good sign as it means you have internalized the vibes of that language in their own and original context, rather than through American sensibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, English to Korean flashcards will be helpful at the beginning, but the ideal is to eventually learn things as a budding Korean does: exclusively in Korean and via trial and error and proper participation. Of course, one never truly forgets about English because Korean has many loan words and phrases, but even these things should be separately internalized (and pronounced) as Koreans do natively, and not as shared words of different languages. Indeed, one will find some English words don&amp;rsquo;t have quite the same contextual usage in English as they do as loan words in Korean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, I would also discourage using question-and-answer formats where there is a reliance on translation to English (e.g., Duolingo&amp;rsquo;s multiple choice questions to translate Korean into English), as these just further the agenda of developing an &amp;ldquo;English translation engine&amp;rdquo; in your mind, rather than internalizing the language. Cognitively, for an English-thinking mind, they&amp;rsquo;re also easier to complete and so give a false impression that you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable in the language, when you&amp;rsquo;re merely comfortable translating it to English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the same reason, I would also avoid watching things with English subtitles as your mind very quickly &amp;ldquo;turns off&amp;rdquo; the other language and pretty much hears things in English (e.g., white people who&amp;rsquo;ve watched thousands of hours of anime but don&amp;rsquo;t even know the most basic words in Japanese).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>clothing</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/fashion/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/fashion/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;broad-themes&#34;&gt;broad themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emphasis on casual/comfy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somewhat averse to dressing overtly like typical academic/nerd or techbro.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not preppy or formal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a little edge is welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mostly neutral and darker colors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;somewhat of a preference for monochrome outfits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a lot of black color.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in past, tended more towards minimalism, normcore but this is not fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slim fit or baggy can both be good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broad-styles-which-appeal-to-me&#34;&gt;broad styles which appeal to me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Korean men casual normcore/streetwear-lite (i.e., what is trendy there nowadays).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;athleisure/sportswear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?client=firefox-b-1-d&amp;amp;sca_esv=577622371&amp;amp;q=casual+tech+wear&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;source=lnms&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjW69GIx5uCAxXYD1kFHdO2AjUQ0pQJegQIDRAB&amp;amp;biw=1440&amp;amp;bih=781&amp;amp;dpr=2&#34;&gt;techwear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://old.reddit.com/r/malefashionadvice/comments/2cilo9/modernist_streetwear_style_guide/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;modernist&amp;rdquo; streetwear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K0Unn3EojhA&#34;&gt;james scholz&lt;/a&gt; (youtuber)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://old.reddit.com/r/malefashionadvice/comments/1rd421/goth_ninja_guide_20/&#34;&gt;goth ninja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pinterest.com/amaryllischan96/ff/&#34;&gt;pinterest album&lt;/a&gt; I created which will be updated over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;specific-items-might-be-good-to-have&#34;&gt;specific items might be good to have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more baggy/oversized clothing in general like oversized tees and jeans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;joggers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sweatshorts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hoodies (non-neutral colors are also good)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;distressed denim (in black or light blue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;light bomber jackets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;carpenter pants/jeans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cargo pants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;baggy corduroy pants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black denim jacket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;camo stuff?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slides/sandals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sneakers (maybe high-top)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beanie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ribbed tank top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non-neutral color sweatshirts/jumpers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tees/sweatshirts with non-advertisement graphics or vintage statements (better but not imperative if mean something personally interesting to me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;running shorts (not for fashion but for running)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;measurements&#34;&gt;measurements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shoe size: 10.5, pant size: 33/32,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;sources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;brands I&amp;rsquo;ve bought from in past: express, asos (online), banana republic, h&amp;amp;m, uniqlo, everlane, oak+fort, muji, pull&amp;amp;bear,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thrift: depop, grailed, ebay, r/malefashionmarket,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Dino&#39;s Exercise Guide</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/exercise/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/exercise/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;I present two full-body workouts that can be alternated on a 2-day/week schedule. Each workout is hyperlinked to a timestamped video showing the correct form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main focus of these workouts is on compound movements (e.g., squats, bench press, shoulder press, deadlifts, pullups) which work multiple muscles simultaneously and promote stabilizers. The exact ordering of exercises in each workout is not super important, but I would generally try to start with the big compound exercises (e.g., starting with squats in A or deadlifts in B) and then finish with the &amp;ldquo;smaller&amp;rdquo; isolation exercises (e.g., curls). If it makes more sense to move around or switch some exerices because of equipment availability or time constraints, then feel free to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also designed this workout to only require dumbbells, a bench, and some cable machines, i.e. no barbell or power rack required. If a cable machine is unavailable, even still I provide substitutions which can be done with free weights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting out, I would first sit down and try to read or watch a video about every exercise here. For each exercise, you should know what muscles are involved and should be engaged as you are doing the exercise. As you are doing said exercise, over time you should be able to notice these muscles &amp;ldquo;activated&amp;rdquo; or engaged in said exercise, and this can be a rough check for whether you are doing it properly or not.
For each exercise, I would learn the form first and get it down pat using the lightest weight or even no weight. Then, I would try to find what weight I can do it for 3 sets of 6-12 reps for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to experiment and substitute or modify the exercises as you see fit, and however best makes sense for your goals, time constraints, and available equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workout-a&#34;&gt;Workout A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squats (&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/MeIiIdhvXT4?t=69&#34;&gt;goblet squats&lt;/a&gt; OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bwhl_9jN_3o&#34;&gt;bulgarian split squats&lt;/a&gt;): 3×8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/3kkS62sIw9M?t=10&#34;&gt;Dumbbell Bench Press&lt;/a&gt;: 3×8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rows (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IzoCF_b3cIY&#34;&gt;seated cable rows&lt;/a&gt; OR bent-over dumbbell rows, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.muscleandstrength.com/exercises/one-arm-dumbbell-row.html&#34;&gt;with bench&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.muscleandstrength.com/exercises/bent-over-dumbbell-row.html&#34;&gt;standing&lt;/a&gt;): 3×8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qEwKCR5JCog&amp;amp;t=49s&#34;&gt;Dumbbell Shoulder Press&lt;/a&gt;: 3×8-10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pullups OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0oeIB6wi3es&#34;&gt;Lat-Pulldowns&lt;/a&gt;: 3x6-10 (but adjust this depending on how many pullups you can do; if you can&amp;rsquo;t do 5, see below advice section).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vl5nUdE9mWM&#34;&gt;Leg Curls&lt;/a&gt; OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m0AIU1dCVkU&#34;&gt;Glute Ham Raises&lt;/a&gt; OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gys7gqxvSDQ&#34;&gt;Good Mornings&lt;/a&gt;: 3×8-10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8WL0m0vLAPo&#34;&gt;Triceps Pushdowns&lt;/a&gt; OR &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nRiJVZDpdL0&#34;&gt;Overhead Tricep Extension&lt;/a&gt;: 3×10-15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bicep Curls (pick your favorite variant): 3×10-15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;workout-b&#34;&gt;Workout B&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.muscleandstrength.com/exercises/dumbbell-stiff-leg-deadlift.html&#34;&gt;Stiff-Leg Dumbbell Deadlift&lt;/a&gt;: 3×6-8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pullups OR Lat-Pulldowns: 3×6-10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/0G2_XV7slIg?t=50&#34;&gt;Incline Dumbbell Press&lt;/a&gt;: 3×8-10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rows (see above): 3×8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lCxa9WTr5lU?t=10&#34;&gt;Dumbbell Lunge&lt;/a&gt;: 3×10-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vNQ7-WBDUKA&#34;&gt;Dumbbell Lateral Raises&lt;/a&gt;: 3×10-15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-M4-G8p8fmc&#34;&gt;Calf Raises&lt;/a&gt;: 4×8-15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abs&lt;/strong&gt;: can be supersetted anywhere in the above. My favorite to superset are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(weighted) crunches or decline crunches 3x8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leg raises: 3x8-12&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq-general-advice-and-things-ive-learned-over-the-years&#34;&gt;FAQ, general advice, and things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How many reps should I do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exact number of reps for each set is not really important and, as you can see above, for most exercises I keep it in the 8-12 range. The most important thing is that the weight and rep count feels strenuous enough that each set is near your limit, i.e. you can do the set but only have 1-2 reps left in the tank. Starting out, you may feel that the third set is much harder than the first set for the same weight and rep count. This is not uncommon, and thus many people do sets in decreasing rep-counts like 12, 10, 8 reps with the same weight. Find what makes sense for you and the weights you have available to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other extreme, you also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be failing at the last rep of every set. This means your sets are too hard and you will likely be too fatigued to do that set successfully the next time. This is also dangerous in the long-term as it promotes breaking form. The sweet spot in difficulty is, again, having 1-2 reps left in the tank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How long should I rest?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2-3 minute rest times between sets are common. Resting longer is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a bad thing; in fact, it is very common for people to not rest long enough which contributes to quick burnout on later sets. If you are resting too little or feel like you don&amp;rsquo;t need any rest at all between sets, then you&amp;rsquo;re not lifting heavy enough to meaningfully build muscle. If you finished a set, barely being able to complete the last rep or even failing to do the last rep, then you should rest longer than usual. In fact, if this is occurring often, you should lower the weight (see above discussion about what weight/rep to choose). Heavy compound lifts (e.g., deadlifts or squats) done for small number of reps (6-8) naturally also require longer rest times as these are going to be the most strenuous lifts for your body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just use a timer to record my rest times, but most people just play by the feel of their bodies to know if they are rested enough to do another set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I superset all my exercises?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supersetting is generally recommended for complementary exercises which work different muscles (e.g., push exercises with pull exercises, or upper body with lower body). It is good for building endurance and saving time, but will definitely fatigue your lifts even if using complementary exercises. Just keep this in mind as you track your progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I improve and build muscle/strength?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, you should try to at least roughly remember or recall how many reps you do for each exercise and what weight you used for each set. I just write these down for every workout. Then, your goal is &lt;em&gt;progressive overload&lt;/em&gt;, or to improve either the weights or reps from each week to week. Sometimes, this will be very miniscule like moving from 10 lb at 12,10,8 reps to 10 lb at 12,10,9 reps but even that still counts. Be wary that if you increase the weight, you will often have to lower the rep counts, e.g. it might make more sense to jump from 3x12 at 10 lb to 3x6-8 at 15 lb since 3x12 at 15 lb might be too dramatic of a difference to acclimate to in one week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, there will be weeks where you find you can&amp;rsquo;t improve from the week before, or that you&amp;rsquo;ve even gone down in reps/weight from the week before (can occur from stress, lack of sleep, improper diet). &lt;em&gt;This is normal&lt;/em&gt; and you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t worry. What&amp;rsquo;s more important is the long-term progress and how you are improving on a scale of months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to seriously build muscle, you should be getting at least 0.8 g of protein per lb of body mass (i.e., 80-90 g for someone who is 100-110 lb). I&amp;rsquo;ll write a separate guide on diet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if I can&amp;rsquo;t do 5 pullups or a small number of reps of an exercise at the lowest weight?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if your one-set max on pull-ups is 5-6, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing 3x(5-6) pullups in your workout as per the above advice on not making each set too hard. If doing 3x6 of pullups is way too hard for you, I would start by doing 3x8-12 of negatives and/or dead-hangs (easier than pullups but will quickly get you to doing 5 solid pullups consistently), or assisted pullups, or lat pull downs instead. Only once you are able to do 8-10 pullups in one go would i start incorporating them into the workout at 3x(5-6).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also adjust the pullup position to make it easier. Chin-ups (where your palms are turned inside facing you) are easiest, then the neutral grip (palms facing each other), then the palms facing outward grip in order of difficulty. So, if you can only do 8-10 chin-ups, start with chin-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also incorporate more sets of curls and rows (e.g., doing 3 sets of cable rows and then doing 3 sets of dumbbell rows) which will also contribute to your pullup strength as you get better at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if on another exercise you find you can&amp;rsquo;t even do it 6-8 solid reps with the lowest dumbbell weight, then you will need to find a way to do the exercise in an alternative easier way where you can build strength on a 3x6-12 basis. How to do this will depend on the exercise and require research (feel free to ask me).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can I run while lifting weights?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do light running on the same day before a lift, but doing a strenuous run before you lift will most likely severely fatigue your lifts. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to run on the same day as lifting, I like to run afterwards. Note that lifting first will inevitably weaken your run, but after a while as my body gets used to lifting, I barely notice this effect while running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the best way to get abs?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a common misconception that abs exceptionally require very high volume, e.g. hundreds of crunches per workout, to build. This is false. Abs should be trained like any other muscle, at roughly 3x8-12 ranges once/twice a week. Like every muscle, the exercise should be adjusted based on difficulty. If you can pump out a hundred crunches without breaking a sweat, then doing 3x8-12 of ordinary crunches makes no sense and you should be doing weighted crunches or some other exercise that gives more resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, getting visible abs is mostly a matter of body fat percentage and thus depends on caloric deficits to lose body fat. Ab exercises are mostly about building core strength and not about making abs &amp;ldquo;more visible&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tips for form and safety?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For mastering form of the big compound lifts, I&amp;rsquo;d carefully read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stronglifts.com/5x5/#Exercises&#34;&gt;Stronglifts guide&lt;/a&gt; on each exercise. For compound lifts at low reps, it&amp;rsquo;s generally recommended to stretch a lot and do several sets of warmup gradually building up to your target weight at the first set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, for all exercises, you should grip the dumbbell as tight as possible to minimize the work your wrists have to do while performing the exercise. For press exercises (i.e., bench press or shoulder press) you should &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; bend your wrist and should try to rest the dumbbell on the heel of your wrist, rather than closer to your fingers. See also the &lt;a href=&#34;https://stronglifts.com/bench-press/#Wrists&#34;&gt;wrist advice on the bench press guide&lt;/a&gt; which also applies to dumbbells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for dumbbell press exercises, try not to do them with your arms laterally to your side as this puts a lot of pressure on your shoulder and rotator cuffs. For example, in the bench press, you should be pressing the dumbbells diagonally and your arms should not be perpendicular to your torso, but instead making a 45-75 degree angle with your sides (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NCSVzCpEtx8?t=177&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). The same applies to the shoulder press: bring your arms a little bit forward (at roughly a 75 degree angle) past your torso when shoulder pressing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are experiencing shoulder pain from press exercises, I would immediately stop and do a thorough double check of my form. I&amp;rsquo;ve also had success incorporating &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LoBBo1dtY6I&#34;&gt;band pull-aparts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IndIttUTNMU&#34;&gt;face-pulls&lt;/a&gt; (the latter can be done with a cable machine or a resistance band) into both my warmups and even between sets of shoulder press and bench press to help my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the dumbbell shoulder press can be done seated or standing. With the seated, you can generally press more weight because you don&amp;rsquo;t have to stabilize your back, whereas the standing forces you to stabilize more. The choice is yours. However, when doing standing presses, make sure to clench your butt (which keeps your back neutral) and try not to lean back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>how I curbed MD</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/quitmd/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/quitmd/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;The following tips have helped me curb maladaptive daydreaming, or at least the most heinous instances where MD is the primary activity of focus. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve completely gotten rid of moments where I&amp;rsquo;m listening to music and pacing around the room while daydreaming. However, I should stress that one isn&amp;rsquo;t going to get rid of MD completely. As I said in my earlier post, it&amp;rsquo;s really a manifestation of near-unconscious thoughts, such as the strong anxieties around one&amp;rsquo;s social standing or a strong limerence/obsession with a fantasy. To &amp;ldquo;re-wire&amp;rdquo; your thinking or to stop thinking about an obsession are more daunting challenges, and by &amp;ldquo;curbing MD&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m just talking about getting rid of the egregious indulgences where one is undeniably wasting time and going into a daydream trance while barely being aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, the following advice will actually help re-wire your thinking and rid yourself of the unconscious processes driving MD as well. But, that will be slower, less deliberate, and so require patience. For example, I still catch myself daydreaming even without music when I&amp;rsquo;m on a walk, or a run, or waiting in line somewhere, or pacing back and forth while resting between sets. You can still catch yourself amidst these moments and shortcircuit the process, much in the same way you become aware in meditation, but it will still happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just get rid of music&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, high-tempo and very upbeat music (usually dance music of some kind) was the main trigger and backdrop for my MD. So, I just decided to stop listening to these kinds of music at all times in my life. The only music I allow in my life now is the classical channel on the radio while driving or lofi/chill beats, ambient jazz, or bossa nova (at very low volumes). In other words, music which will not trigger MD. Actually, my association of this particular kind of music and MD is so strong that it actually worked to my favor, because it makes daydreaming with any other kind of music or silence much less appealing. To many, this advice is hard to hear because they really enjoy music and want to believe that somehow it&amp;rsquo;s possible to disentangle music from MD. I too loved listening to upbeat music, especially while exercising. It literally changes the entire atmosphere of whatever I&amp;rsquo;m doing. It can make me run longer and harder, lift more weight, and motivate me like nothing else can (and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried stimulants). Sometimes, it&amp;rsquo;s almost as if I can feel the aural dopamine surging through me as the song hits just the right moments, and I am very prone to getting goosebumps in dramatic moments. It&amp;rsquo;s actually quite a strong drug for me and many others. There are many reasons outside of MD why I would encourage less music listening in general and less &amp;ldquo;putting on music as background noise in your day to day life&amp;rdquo;, as I think it poses a unique harm in your conception of self, but this is the subject of a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop keeping track of what others are doing, or get rid of triggers for your anxiety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will almost always mean spending less time on the internet. I never really noticed it for many years, but my MD often came about in response to a heightened moment of anxiety. For example, if I was on the internet and found out that one of my peers won a prestigious award or was hired for some nice job, then I would become jealous and anxious about my own future, and would resort to MD. If reading something online triggered in me insecurities about my appearance, or romantic woes, or my incompetence in some social regard, then I would resort to MD. Even merely reading certain kinds of news, or discussions about certain subject matters among anonymous nobodies on the internet could trigger anxiety, and then MD. You may see that the common theme is the internet. So, I just decided to get rid of all social media, all &amp;ldquo;recommendation feeds&amp;rdquo; (e.g., anything fed to you by a recommendation engine which is usually the front page of any major social media website), and all instances of &amp;ldquo;snooping/stalking around on the internet to find out information about other people&amp;rdquo;. I even made it a rule to never google the names of other people, unless it is for a very specific query. Also, it goes without saying that I stopped reading all forms of news. This has led to an &lt;strong&gt;enormous boost in my well-being&lt;/strong&gt; and a new found calmness that did not exist before. And this advice is also quite difficult to hear for many terminally online &amp;ldquo;information/consumption&amp;rdquo;-addicts because it tackles issues that go above and beyond MD, but it really has made a difference for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many objections that could come up in response to this. One might say that this is a very escapist tactic and is kind of like running away from the world to avoid feeling insecure or anxious. I&amp;rsquo;d respond that perpetual engagement with all the internet, constantly being anxious and bedridden with worry, and becoming so easily emotionally undulated by the most frivolous of things you read and see are what is escapist. I understand that some of the goals of mindfulness and shadow work are to confront your darker feelings, and not be afraid to embrace their reality. I have no confusion about this: I am not in denial of any of these anxieties or how obsessed I am with comparing myself to other people. There&amp;rsquo;s a parable or saying about drinking wine mindfully, and so really noticing the stupor of drunkenness, and then electing to getting rid of the drinking once you become fully aware of what kind of effect it has on your body. I&amp;rsquo;m doing the exact same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One might also argue that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to curate your internet experience as to be wholesome or to only read about things which do not instill anxiety and insecurity. That&amp;rsquo;s great if it&amp;rsquo;s possible, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to do this and don&amp;rsquo;t have any desire to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One might also argue that it&amp;rsquo;s good to keep abreast of what others are doing and read the news, because it is the worldly thing to do. Even independent of anxiety or maladaptive daydreaming, I&amp;rsquo;d still completely disagree and will write a future post about this. I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t really have to say too much though. There is great recognition in our culture nowadays that social media and the internet have outsized negative effects on mental well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I still talk to people in real life, and I don&amp;rsquo;t forcefully restrict subjects of conversation to shield myself from anxiety or triggers, as that would make conversation awkward. I find that talking to people in real life is actually the best way to &amp;ldquo;keep abreast of their lives&amp;rdquo; or find out about the news. Snooping around on the internet to find out about other people&amp;rsquo;s lives without their consent is at this point just creepy and perverted to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindfulness meditation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost cliche advice at this point if you&amp;rsquo;re already familiar with the wellness/self-improvement space, but it really does work. The typical fantasies, anxieties, and worries about the future that arise in MD will also arise in meditation. It&amp;rsquo;s the best time and place to practice becoming aware of these things, without indulging in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow work and journaling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While meditation is good for becoming aware that you&amp;rsquo;re MD-ing at all, shadow work and journaling are what I find most helpful for actually dissecting the reasons I MD and what uncovering what underlying malfunctions give rise to these phenomena. All the understanding in what I wrote about success anxiety and how MD works for me in the previous post came about from shadow work. You have to be careful with shadow work, because if you have an overactive mind (which often MD-ers do), it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to fall into the trap of over-psychoanalyzing and over-medicalizing yourself. I used to do this myself. It&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid doing shadow work in a very emotional or stressful time, and you need to find a time where you&amp;rsquo;ll be calm, measured, and non-judgmental. I find that using simple shadow work prompts/questions, or bulleting simple and short sentences (such as early memories of when I would MD, or when I would feel anxious about something) work best. What has never worked well is just free-form writing paragraph after paragraph which is very unstructured and quickly devolves into emotional rambling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being guided by another person (such as a therapist) can also help protect against this trap. However, I have no experience with therapy and am admittedly very privileged to have never needed to. But, it&amp;rsquo;s worth trying if you find it very daunting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Become more interested in life and doing things in general&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my MD was mostly a cope for anxiety, there was also a degree of boredom and restlessness which often triggered it. The antidote to this is to just have a fulfilling and interesting life that you look forward to participating in, thus decreasing the &amp;ldquo;need&amp;rdquo; and allure of MD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that, as I&amp;rsquo;ve taken my life much more seriously throughout the past year, and just become more invested in things like doing my job well, fitness, health/diet, cooking, refining my computer setup, learning other languages, reading books, etc., I have just become less and less motivated to MD at all. Note that I am expressly &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; promoting hustling to becoming as productive as possible, or becoming a fastidious and obedient worker drone, or optimizing your time schedule to squeeze every minute of output. I&amp;rsquo;m against all these aspects of self-improvement culture (again, a subject for another post), and instead encourage you to select for yourself what should be the serious and fulfilling parts of your life. I sincerely hope it is not internet browsing and consuming content though, as per the above advice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>how to manage anger</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/anger/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/anger/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;I have always dealt with uncontrollable provocations of anger, usually in response to minor setbacks in my day to day life, such as being cut off in traffic or having my time wasted for various logistical reasons. It often involves cursing very loudly and saying all kinds of extreme epithets about the culprit du jour and stomping around, e.g. slamming doors loudly or slamming things onto the table. Many of these are caused by the annoyances of some technologicla device, which I slam onto a floor and break violently into pieces, as if to punish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think, as a child, my anger was not so intense, but it recently became more intense as an adult. Sometimes, I find myself cursing loudly in public because I am irritated that I, say, got on the wrong train. In the past, I would have been too embarrassed to have other people hear me, but now when I get very angry, my compulsion to be loud overwhelms even that restraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally have found the following tips helpful for curbing anger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laugh and have some childlike levity about the situation, and about life in general. When I am in the heat of the moment and start laughing, it automatically changes the vibe of the environment. And it is usually easy to laugh because I am, in that moment, acting so cartoonishly and obnoxiously angry that one cannot help but laugh. Sometimes I can even laugh at the actual discomfort of my situation and what caused me to be angry about it, that is laugh at the absurdity of it and sort of laugh &amp;ldquo;in awe&amp;rdquo; at the power of it to sway my emotions with such acceleration. Funnily, the more angry and theatrical your anger, the better this advice works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow yourself to do the yelling and cursing and slamming. That is fine as an outlet, although one should be careful about doing this in front of other people who may become scared or confused. But, after doing this, you can pause and meditate on what you are feeling, and the anger will start subsiding in that moment. Sometimes, as said above, an unintuitive thing can happen. The more obnoxious the yelling and cursing is, the easier it is to calm myself down, often by reflecting on the above tip and laughing at how obnoxious it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledge that time and money are not important, and should not be the source of your anger. In my normal life, I am very frugal and stingy, and hate having my money wasted for no reason, even if it is a small amount. I also hate having my time wasted even 10 minutes, e.g. in traffic. However, when I am really angry, I try not to let these things &lt;strong&gt;remain&lt;/strong&gt; the source of my anger. If there is a straightforward way to alleviate the situation by expensing money or time (e.g., I have to go to the store and buy this $50 super-special cleaner to clean this mess on my rug for 45 minutes), then I might still be angry, but I try to truly let go of the &amp;ldquo;$50&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;45 minutes&amp;rdquo; as quickly as possible. If I am still angry, I let myself by angry. But, usually, by letting go of the anxiety about money or the anxiety aobut time, I find the anger has already subsided. In fact, I usually find I quite appreciate having 45 minutes to take a rest while cleaning the rug and contemplate various things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In much the same vein as (3), appreciate the opportunities in your life to slow down and take a break, even if it is to handle something unsavory that is not your fault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat people or inanimate objects like animals or children, that is with tenderness and a wizened non-judgmental objectivity. That is, don&amp;rsquo;t take anything personally. I tend to be very snarky, sarcastic, and cynical when it comes to other people&amp;rsquo;s mainstream lifestyle choices. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t really start as anger per se, but it can quickly devolve into anger when it affects my life. For example, maybe someone really cares about how we are dressed at some occasion because they are really anxious about their social standing. I don&amp;rsquo;t care about how I am dressed and perceived, and become first annoyed and then venomously irate about having to accommodate this other person&amp;rsquo;s anxieties. It is easy to start cursing them out and insulting every disagreement I have with their identity. However, we would consider a parent who curses out their child and gets inappropriately angry at every little mishap to be an immature and irresponsible parent. We would similarly consider a pet owner who curses out their pet and starts throwing things around the house. The pet or child is not even going to comprehend why you are angry. They are not even really sentient, merely operating on whims and sensations which predate them by millennia. What about a person who destroys and commits violence against their computer, or other inanimate objects, for being the source of their annoyance? This is even less reasonable, because the culprit is truly inanimate and cannot respond to anything you do. However, other people in real life have sensations which ebb and flow with yours, and if you are angry they will, like a child or pet, react and often become scared or defensive. We should treat other adults and technology and inanimate objects like we treat children, with tenderness and care. I think we should not be so quick to be violent (either physically or verbally/emotionally). There is this strange belief that we have as adults earned &amp;ldquo;the right&amp;rdquo; to not be tender with other adults or with inanimate objects because &amp;ldquo;they can take it&amp;rdquo;, but alas we are all children, and still growing and making mistakes, and still being unconsciously swayed by mysterious forces since time immemorial. Appreciating this fact has made me much more empathetic towards other people, and become less angry about having to make sacrifices or accommodate other people&amp;rsquo;s anxieties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>my experience with maladaptive daydreaming</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/daydreams/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/daydreams/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success and MD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always had this image of a successful person on my mind, largely informed by other people&amp;rsquo;s ideas of success. A successful person is healthy. A successful person has a lot of friends, and is worldly, and well-read, and smart, and attractive, and unique. A successful person is competent and wealthy. The exact traits can vary, but this general image is always on my mind, and infiltrates every facet of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I judge success for myself is usually not based on how much I adhere to this image, for it is not really possible to do this since the image is vague to begin with and since the scale has no upper limit with no real epitome (i.e., you can always be more successful). But, rather, it is based on how much &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; I adhere to this image than other people, or how much more they adhere to it than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I maladaptively daydream, I am actually always thinking of this idea of success. Sometimes, I am just maladaptively daydreaming out of loneliness, but even these instances are actually about success in my opinion. Or, at least, all my maladaptive daydreams have evolved into being about success at this point in my life. My earliest instances of MD were mainly about having friends because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any in real life, particularly not at school. For example, in fifth grade, I would MD that the characters from Harry Potter were real people and my friends since I was obsessed with Harry Potter at the time. In seventh grade, I would MD that various characters from various shows and internet content I watched were real people and my friends. I think initially this was purely out of loneliness and my lack of close friendships. However, when I indulged in this same maladaptive daydream later in life (including now), it is more about &amp;ldquo;comparing how many friends I have and the quality of my friendships&amp;rdquo; with other people. Stated another way, maladaptive daydreaming to me is a coping mechanism in response to the attendant anxiety that results from my obsession with comparing myself to other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is in stark contrast to many other accounts of maladaptive daydreaming I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Others who maladaptively daydream really are just lonely, or have overactive imaginations with a propensity for fantasy, characer, and world building. I share some of these traits, but over the years I really do feel like obsession with comparing myself to others is the predominant theme behind my MD. At the same time, the type of MDing I do here is extremely popular if you peruse any first-hand discussion on maladaptive daydreaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a young age, I remember being very jealous when finding out that someone, who I initially pegged to be a loner like me, actually had close friends or a lot of friends. And, a lot of this jealousy arises from conceptions about how cool or successful their friends are, which in my mind dictated the quality of said person&amp;rsquo;s friendships. For example, the feelings would intensify if I learned that this person was friends with attractive or smart people. I also remember being very jealous and confused (maybe even angry) when finding out that someone who was &amp;ldquo;good at school&amp;rdquo; or one of the smart kids had a lot of friends. This confused me because I believed I was good at school, and one of the smart kids. Yet, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any friends. So, I thought that one cannot be attained without sacrificing the other, which was the only hypothesis which proved I am still &amp;ldquo;as successful&amp;rdquo; as other people while minimizing who is successful: i.e., this was a very roundabout and self-serving coping mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as I saw more people who are in fact smart and in fact have many friends, these two qualities became inextricably linked. So much so that &amp;ldquo;having friends&amp;rdquo; became an idea of success to me, and I would resent it in other people. This was because of a larger phenomenon where I resented success when it was not in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I daydreamed about success in both of these regards. I daydreamed that I was smart and attractive, because I lacked these things in my actual life. And I daydreamed that I had a lot of successful friends, and was renowned, because this was sorely lacking in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, it always felt to me like the daydreaming was &amp;ldquo;in response&amp;rdquo; to this imaginary version of the people I am jealous of judging me. I would see these people who I envied, who were smart and attractive and had a lot of friends. And, in my mind, they would be judging me and condescending to me, just like how I condescended on others who lacked the qualities that I possessed. I really hated the feeling of being judged like this, or the feeling that these other people knew how much of a loser I am. I even grew to hate being perceived by other people at all (or at least feeling that I am).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think children and teenagers often get this kind of sentiment. They refuse to believe their doddering and bumbling parents understand anything about them. They have to be contrarians and listen to the loudest, most obnoxious and profane music. They refuse to believe that their mates at school can, with harsh and laser-like precision, quantify their exact place on the social pecking order. The pathological liar is often born in response, concocting the fake girlfriend who goes to a different school, writing the Mary Sue fan fiction where everyone claps to their prowess, going off about &amp;ldquo;sigma males&amp;rdquo; and obscure internet rabbit holes of which only they can cultivate expertise, while others remain plebeians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My daydreams are a similar kind of &amp;ldquo;response&amp;rdquo; to judgment that a pariah does at this age. And, it&amp;rsquo;s an intensely bitter and pathetically self-comforting kind of response. It is like I am very desperately sending a plea to the outside world (maybe to myself): &amp;ldquo;Oh please, look at me! I am actually cool. I actually have friends! See? I am not such a loser!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me illustrate with some personal examples. However, before doing so, let me first clarify that although the tone of this post is getting very acerbic and everything is written in the first-person tense, everything I wrote above should actually be in the past-tense as MD doesn&amp;rsquo;t really afflict my life anymore thanks to steps I&amp;rsquo;ve taken which I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss later. If the tone here strikes you as overly cynical or negative, just understand I am indeed deliberately trying to convey that emotion because that&amp;rsquo;s the kind of emotional atmosphere that these obsessions propelled me towards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In high school, the other smart and successful kids who I perceived as my competition were all friends with each other, and less with me. I mean, they were more than genial to me, but we were always kind of detached and maybe I was just awkward or shy or just said too much weird out-there shit. But, this made me intensely bitter, and the green monster of jealousy lurking in my soul could only be abated by MD&amp;rsquo;ing myself into a fantasy world where I had more friends than them, and those friends were more attractive and smarter and successful in every regard, as was I (often and conveniently the most so in every regard).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In high school, I had a crush on someone who had a crush on someone else, who I regarded as more successful than me. This made me intensely bitter, and I daydreamed that everything was reversed in the way one would hope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In college, I became jealous upon finding out that someone else my age knew more about math, or went to a better college, or was taking harder courses, or lifted weights, or literally any frivolously nonsensical point of comparison. I daydreamed that everything was reversed in the way one would hope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In grad school, the other grad students (who I perceived as my competition) were all more friendly to each other than to me. Yet again, they were more than genial to me, and clearly curious about who I am as well, but I could not help but be intensely jealous and MD myself into a world very similar to point (1) above. Sometimes, I would even just daydream that I was closer friends with them, and that I was the most popular and attractive and successful person in the group (and the world lol).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you see the pattern? The daydream always arises &lt;em&gt;in response&lt;/em&gt; to some insecurity in real life. And it is always the same insecurity, one about how I am lacking in comparison to other people and how those other people might be perceiving me. Note that every single maladaptive daydream is not actually caused by anything in the real world, or the environment which surrounds me. There is not even a shred of empathy or curiosity exhibited for the other real people involved. Instead, it is an exercise of narcissism, and the most obnoxious and boring kind of narcissism, centered on how I am more successful than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Discussions on MD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dislike the mainstream portrayals and impressions of maladaptive daydreaming, such as the movie &amp;ldquo;Secret Life of Walter Mitty&amp;rdquo; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/04/05/598365217/invisibilia-when-daydreaming-gets-in-the-way-of-real-life&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; episode of the Invisibilia podcast. Yes, these portrayals do involve a similar kind of narcissism and self-centeredness as the kind I&amp;rsquo;m talking about here. And, they both acknowledge the pitfalls of spending too much time in the dream realm. But, I disagree with the messaging and implications therein which shows daydreams are for the most part just quixotic, but innocent and harmless, fleeting phenomena of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I contend that the type of MD I practice is actually &lt;strong&gt;seriously harmful&lt;/strong&gt; to your mental well-being and &lt;strong&gt;detrimental&lt;/strong&gt; to your ability to compassionately socialize with other people. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s not about going on adventures to other planets with quirky fictional characters. It&amp;rsquo;s not about creativity, or writing fiction in my mind. It&amp;rsquo;s unbridled narcissism, plain and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about as stories in and of themselves? In my opinion, just about every maladaptive daydream I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read or heard recorded (including mine own and others) possesses &lt;strong&gt;close to zero literary value&lt;/strong&gt; and in fact would have a negative effect to anyone who naively consumed them, as they risk the reader associating with the obnoxious self-centeredness depicted in the story. Most are written like really bad fan-fiction, filled to the brim with wishful thinking and wish fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, daydreaming is pure and wasteful self-absorption. There is not a single activity in my life that is anywhere close to being more narcissistic than daydreaming. The contents of the daydreams are always derivative, uninteresting, and completely predictable. Over time, it has made me extremely self-conscious, to the point where I will schizophrenically read even the most innocuous occurences as slights against my ego. It has made me preoccupied with success, in all the most vapid ways I define it, and with myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ll state this another way which may be more convincing to many. In recent years, I have become very enamored by the idea of mindfulness, with regards to personal development and self-therapy. Over the course of my life, I have thought about other forms of self-therapy, such as Christian prayer or self-denial or hyper-rationalism or frequent journaling, and none of those things came close to the idea of mindfulness in really properly and thoroughly addressing the key internal conflicts of my life. Mindfulness is, I have found, the only &amp;ldquo;way of viewing reality&amp;rdquo; or type of &amp;ldquo;levelheadedness&amp;rdquo; that goes well with my intuition on how to calmly behave in life. I learned what it was, in a formal &amp;ldquo;read about it in an article&amp;rdquo;-sense a very long time ago but only got around to actually start seriously practicing it recently. I&amp;rsquo;m still a beginner, but already I can see the value of it, as can many others since you can find it in many places where personal development and wellness are concerned. A full discussion of what mindfulness has done for me is for another post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the point about MD is as follows. I cannot think of a single activity in my day to day life that is the furthest away from mindfulness as maladaptive daydreaming. For me, the two are polar opposites. Maladaptive daydreaming involves entering a trance where you are engaged with, and manifesting in your mind, whatever emotion you&amp;rsquo;re currently feeling as strongly as possible. I actually can&amp;rsquo;t think of another moment in life where you&amp;rsquo;re more absorbed by, and fully &amp;ldquo;living out&amp;rdquo;, your emotion than MD. Even when I&amp;rsquo;m occasionally very angry (see my post on anger), at least I&amp;rsquo;m still angry about something happening in reality and I&amp;rsquo;m tethered to the sensations of reality. To contrast, MD is a full untethering of any grounding to sensation or your present moment. It is a transportation of your self to an imaginal realm where your current emotion (usually anxiety) is maximally expressed and visualized. As a metaphor, MD is like &amp;ldquo;full-screening&amp;rdquo; your current emotion/anxiety and wrapping it all the way around your head so that it takes up every inch of your field of view, and there is no perception of anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can perhaps argue that it&amp;rsquo;s possible to MD &amp;ldquo;mindfully&amp;rdquo; as it&amp;rsquo;s possible to do anything mindfully. I concede this is true, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s unusually difficult to do this, more difficult than being mindful in other activities. The sheer emotional inertia of MD really just disallows contemplation in a way unlike other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purported benefits of MD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do argue that MD has some benefits, and I&amp;rsquo;ll address such claims as fairly as I can. I&amp;rsquo;ve already addressed the argument that it can lead to bursts of creativity and inspiration (read: narcissism should be avoided in creativity). And again all my discussion really pertains to the type of MD I introduced which comes about from anxiety and anti-social obsessions. If you really daydream purely about imaginary characters and stories, then maybe it can serve some benefit in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other argument I hear is that, because it is a proper coping mechanism for some kind of trauma or anxiety, it does serve a good in your life. It can soothe your worries about the future, or give you an optimism or self-confidence to deal with the problems in your life. I have definitely felt this in my life. When I&amp;rsquo;m doubtful about how I measure up compared to others, an MD session really instills in me a strong self-assuredness and a resounding belief that things will work in my favor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, in my opinion, these positive feelings that result from MD are &lt;strong&gt;unearned&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;escapist&lt;/strong&gt;. They don&amp;rsquo;t come about from actually confronting the original trauma or anxiety, and instead bypass such tasks. So, it&amp;rsquo;s more akin to hedonistically taking a drug to get a momentary hit of bliss. In my opinion, self-confidence and optimism are not things that should come for free. They should only accompany making measurable progress in the things which bother you, or adequately addressing the very reasons for why you lacked self-confidence or optimism in the first place. Even something as vain as &amp;ldquo;gaining confidence in oneself because one exercises and loses weights and likes their appearance more&amp;rdquo; (which is not without its problems) is infinitely better than the unearned feelings resulting from MD. The former results in some understanding, however dim it may be, that your self-confidence is tied to your feelings about your appearance. On the other hand, MD just gives you self-confidence without just cause, which will lead to much more foolishness and self-centeredness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, it&amp;rsquo;s shown in the few studies on MD that MD really is a confluence of various maladies and can be present in varying circumstances. Throughout this post, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking more to the type of people who have pure-O (&amp;ldquo;obsessive&amp;rdquo;) OCD, rather than people who exhibit MD from perpetual restlessness or the need for stimulation (e.g., people with ADHD). In any circumstance, I&amp;rsquo;m never saying MD is unambiguously the greatest harm in your life. No, it&amp;rsquo;s really just the manifestation of more serious problems in your life and so those should be addressed first. As such, I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;fault&amp;rdquo; anyone for repeatedly engaging in MD. It&amp;rsquo;s just an understandable symptom of more serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Reading List</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/reading/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/reading/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;currently-reading-though-this-list-has-remained-the-same-for-the-last-2-years-and-ill-probably-restart-all-these-books&#34;&gt;Currently reading (though this list has remained the same for the last 2 years and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably restart all these books)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11324722-the-righteous-mind&#34;&gt;The Righteous Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/75812.The_Closing_of_the_American_Mind&#34;&gt;The Closing of the American Mind&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/168668.Catch_22&#34;&gt;Catch-22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41721428-can-t-hurt-me&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t Hurt Me: Master Your Mind and Defy the Odds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-read&#34;&gt;To Read&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nonfiction&#34;&gt;nonfiction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sapiens:_A_Brief_History_of_Humankind&#34;&gt;Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/a&gt; by Noah Yuval Harari.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5895503-the-ego-tunnel&#34;&gt;The Ego Tunnel: The Science of the Mind and the Myth of the Self&lt;/a&gt; by Thomas Metzinger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Culture_of_Narcissism&#34;&gt;The Culture of Narcissism&lt;/a&gt; by Christopher Lasch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Story_of_Art&#34;&gt;The Story of Art&lt;/a&gt; by EH Gombrich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Blank_Slate&#34;&gt;The Blank Slate&lt;/a&gt; by Steven Pinker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/76402.The_Heart_of_Christianity&#34;&gt;The Heart of Christianity: Rediscovering a Life of Faith&lt;/a&gt; by Marcus J. Borg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selected Non-Fictions by Jorge Luis Borges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/306940.Impro&#34;&gt;Impro: Improvisation and the Theatre&lt;/a&gt; by Keith Johnstone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Change_Your_Mind&#34;&gt;how to change your mind&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Pollan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/28820444&#34;&gt;The Elephant in the Brain: Hidden Motives in Everyday Life&lt;/a&gt; by Kevin Simler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Myth_of_the_Rational_Voter&#34;&gt;The Myth of the Rational Voter&lt;/a&gt; by Bryan Caplan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hillbilly_Elegy&#34;&gt;Hillbilly Elegy&lt;/a&gt; by JD Vance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Death_in_the_Haymarket&#34;&gt;Death in the Haymarket&lt;/a&gt; by by James R. Green.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Outsider_(Wilson_book)&#34;&gt;The Outsider&lt;/a&gt; by Colin Wilson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/56829.Hackers&#34;&gt;Hackers: Heroes of the Computer Revolution&lt;/a&gt; by Steven Levy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28597.Prometheus_Rising&#34;&gt;Prometheus Rising&lt;/a&gt; by by Robert Anton Wilson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28597.Prometheus_Rising&#34;&gt;SSOTBME - an essay on magic&lt;/a&gt; by Ramsey Dukes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Against_Method&#34;&gt;Against Method&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Freyerabrand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24113.G_del_Escher_Bach&#34;&gt;Godel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/a&gt; by Douglas Hofstadtler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.versobooks.com/books/2505-psychopolitics&#34;&gt;psychopolitics&lt;/a&gt; by Byung-Chul Han.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intercourse_(book)&#34;&gt;Intercourse&lt;/a&gt; by Andrea Dworkin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13547504-far-from-the-tree&#34;&gt;Far from the Tree: Parents, Children, and the Search for Identity&lt;/a&gt; by Andrew Solomon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/262579.The_Unfolding_of_Language&#34;&gt;The Unfolding of Language: An Evolutionary Tour of Mankind&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Invention&lt;/a&gt; by Guy Deutscher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6601267-the-machinery-of-life&#34;&gt;The Machinery of Life&lt;/a&gt; by David Goodswell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/118397.The_Lucifer_Principle&#34;&gt;The Lucifer Principle: A Scientific Expedition into the Forces of History&lt;/a&gt; by Howard Bloom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/242472.The_Black_Swan&#34;&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly Improbable&lt;/a&gt; bvy Nassim Taleb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6340873-the-evolution-of-god&#34;&gt;The Evolution of God&lt;/a&gt; by Robert Wright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/8130077-the-screwtape-letters&#34;&gt;The Screwtape Letters&lt;/a&gt; by CS Lewis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/381440.The_Society_of_the_Spectacle&#34;&gt;The Society of the Spectacle&lt;/a&gt; by Guy Debord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3203321-stolen-lightning&#34;&gt;Stolen Lightning: The Social Theory of Magic&lt;/a&gt; by Lawrence O&amp;rsquo;Keefe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/80448.On_the_Genealogy_of_Morality&#34;&gt;On the Genealogy of Morality&lt;/a&gt; by Nietzsche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beyond_Good_and_Evil&#34;&gt;Beyond Good and Evil&lt;/a&gt; by Nietzsche.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/118316.A_Thousand_Plateaus&#34;&gt;A Thousand Plateaus: Capitalism and Schizophrenia&lt;/a&gt; by Gilles Deleuze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/118317.Anti_Oedipus&#34;&gt;Anti-Oedipus: Capitalism and Schizophrenia&lt;/a&gt; by Gilles Deleuze&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10838202-fanged-noumena&#34;&gt;Fanged Noumena: Collected Writings, 1987-2007&lt;/a&gt; by Nick Land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4617457-cyclonopedia&#34;&gt;Cyclonopedia: Complicity with Anonymous Materials&lt;/a&gt; by Reza Negarestani&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/1449354.Libido_Dominandi&#34;&gt;Libido Dominandi: Sexual Liberation and Political Control&lt;/a&gt; by Michael E. Jones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/29845449&#34;&gt;The Weird and the Eerie&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Fisher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/49556729&#34;&gt;Politics is for Power&lt;/a&gt; by Eitan Hersh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32081.Albion_s_Seed&#34;&gt;Albion&amp;rsquo;s Seed: Four British Folkways in America (America: A Cultural History, Vol. I)&lt;/a&gt; by David Hackett Fischer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4129848-mastering-the-core-teachings-of-the-buddha&#34;&gt;Mastering the Core Teachings of the Buddha&lt;/a&gt; by Daniel Ingram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/152038.The_Politics_of_Heroin&#34;&gt;The Politics of Heroin: CIA Complicity in the Global Drug Trade&lt;/a&gt; by Alfred W. McCoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/705212.Unforgotten_Dreams&#34;&gt;Unforgotten Dreams: Poems by the Zen Monk Shotetsu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dispelling Wetiko: Breaking the Curse of Evil by Paul Levy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ishmael by Daniel Quinn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiction&#34;&gt;fiction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ficciones&#34;&gt;Ficciones&lt;/a&gt; by Jorge Luis Borges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lovecraft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philip k dick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brave New World.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dune by Frank Herbert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Doppler_(novel)&#34;&gt;Doppler&lt;/a&gt; by Erlend Loe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_of_Leaves&#34;&gt;House of Leaves&lt;/a&gt; by Mark Z. Danieleski.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stories_of_Your_Life_and_Others&#34;&gt;Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;broad-reading-interests&#34;&gt;broad reading interests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am generally interested in fiction or non-fiction about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;religion (especially orthodox Christianity, Buddhism, and Taoism)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple living and stoicism/asceticism and bohemianism and experimental lifestyle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;philosophy, transcendantalism, astrology, the occult, magic, surrealism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;culture war and politics and history and Asian-American culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;but I am open minded about what I read as there are lots of books above that fall outside of my interests or that I &amp;ldquo;disagree&amp;rdquo; with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jos-bookclub-suggested-books&#34;&gt;jo&amp;rsquo;s bookclub suggested books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stories of your life and others - ted chiang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the three body problem - cixin liu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fanged noumena: collected writings 1987-2007, nick land&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the weird and the eerie - mark fisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psychopolitics - byung-chul han&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>what I learned about acne</title>
		<link>https://amaryllisc.github.io/acne_guide/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://amaryllisc.github.io/acne_guide/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/acne&#34;&gt;someone&lt;/a&gt;, acne is a &amp;ldquo;disorder of the hair follicles and sebaceous glands&amp;hellip; sebaceous glands secrete oils to keep the skin moist, but clogged glands (because of buildup in hair follicles) lead to pimples and cysts&amp;rdquo;. The primary causes of acne are agreed to be&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hormone changes (e.g., from menstrual cycles, pregnancy, birth control pills).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain medicines (e.g., corticosteroids, lithium, or barbiturates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A popular hypothesis argues acne is primarily a disease of modern civilization, and in particular, the modern diet. The prevalence of acne among so-called primitives who eat a non-Western diet is near nilch (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/27651516/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1054139X97002772&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12472346/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1054139X97002772&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.lww.com/nutritiontodayonline/Citation/1977/05000/When_the_Eskimo_Comes_to_Town_.7.aspx&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diet&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three major food classes which promote acne seem to be (cf. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4507494/&#34;&gt;Melnik, 2015&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperglycemic carbohydrates (e.g., white and whole wheat bread, white rice, cereal, cakes, sweets, potatoes, watermelon, pineapple).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Milk and dairy products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturated fats including trans-fats (e.g., butter, cheese, ice cream, baked goods) and &lt;em&gt;deficient&lt;/em&gt; omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) (e.g., need enough of fish, seeds, tofu, eggs).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other commonly suspected causes/triggers of acne are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sugar and processed carbs &amp;ndash; these spike insulin levels which induce your inflamed sebaceous glands to produce more sebum which can lead to more clogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soy &amp;ndash; affects estrogen and androgen levels which can also inflame sebaceous glands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peanuts and peanut butter &amp;ndash; contains androgen-like material which can affect hormones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alcohol &amp;ndash; also raises certain hormone levels. It also dehydrates you, drying out your skin (which induces skin to produce more oil&amp;hellip;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gluten (e.g., bread, baked goods, beer, crackers) &amp;ndash; some people have mild gluten allergies manifesting in inflammation/acne and they don&amp;rsquo;t know it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lifestyle-tips&#34;&gt;Lifestyle Tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a gentle cleanser (e.g., Cerave Hydrating Cleanser) &amp;ndash; heavier cleansers dehydrate skin, can cause irritation, and change the natural pH of your skin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moisturize skin often &amp;ndash; as said above in the comment about alcohol, you want to avoid dry skin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink more water (e.g., 3 liters a day is a good amount) &amp;ndash; ditto.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweat more &amp;ndash; sweat flushes out your pores, but probably recommended to wash afterwards so residue does not stick to your skin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
